A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic heals hearts dried by modern society!
تعالج استنتاجات كونان القلوب !التي جفّفها المجتمع الحديث
Today's case is the darkness of night.
تقبع قضيّة اليوم تحت غطاء الليل
Dark mysteries need the light of logic!
!الألغاز المُظلمة ينيرها ضوء الاستنتاج
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
اسمه؟
The Pitch Dark Road Murder Case
جريمة قتل الطريق المُظلم
Wasn't that delicious, Conan-kun?
كان ذلك لذيذاً جدّاً، صحيح يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah!
!أجل
Ugh! You ordered nothing but expensive food!
!يا إلهي، لم تطلبا إلّا الأكل الباهظ
Oh! If it isn't Mori!
!عجباً، إنّه أنت يا موري
Omura! Long time, no see!
!أومورا! مضى وقتٌ طويل
Omura Jun (37)
(أومورا جون (37 زميل قديم لموري، مدير متجر نماذج
You seem as lively as ever.
تبدو مفعماً بالحياة كالمُعتاد
Do you remember Omura-san?
أتذكر أومورا-سان يا كونان-كن؟
Yeah! He's his college friend that we met at the hot springs!
أجل، إنّه صديق العمّ من أيام الجامعة !الذي التقيناه في الينبوع الساخن
This is perfect timing, Mori. I need to talk to you...
.بالمناسبة يا موري، هذه فرصة ممتازة هناك ما أريد الكلام معك بشأنه
What about?
ما هو؟
There's this strange sound outside my apartment every night.
أسمع صوتاً غريباً خارج شقّتي في الليل مؤخراً
A strange sound?
صوت غريب؟
It's a thump, as if something's hitting the outside wall.
إنّه ارتطام، كما لو أصاب شيء الحائط الخارجي
Probably just some kids up to no good.
لعلّها مشاغبة أطفال الحيّ
I thought so too, but there was nobody outside when I checked,
ذلك ما ظننته بدايةً، لكنّي لم أجد أحداً عندما خرجتُ للتفقّد
and it's been going on for a whole week now.
وهذا مستمرّ لأسبوع الآن
A whole week, huh...
أسبوع؟
Why not look into it for him?
لمَ لا نذهب ونتفقد الأمر؟
Please, Mori.
من فضلك يا موري
Alright! Just leave it to the great Mori Kogoro!
!حسناً، دع الأمر للمتحرّي العظيم موري كوغورو
Thank you!
!شكراً لك
Delicious!
!لذيذ
Nothing beats drinking beer with old friends!
!ما أروع الشرب مع صديق بعد غياب
I thought you were here to investigate the weird sound.
ظننتُك أتيت لتحرّي الصوت الغريب
Oh, looks like we're out of beer.
يبدو أنّ الجعّة نفدت
I'll go buy some.
سأذهب لشرائها
No, I'll do that!
!سأذهب أنا
Thank you!
!شكراً جزيلاً
You're disturbing the neighbors!
!أنتَ تزعج الجيران
We're back!
!عدنا
Been waiting for this!
!كنّا بانتظارك
What was that?
ما هذا؟
What happened here?
...ما الذي
Hey, Ikuta. What's wrong?
إيكوتا، ما الخطب؟
Ikuta! Come on, already! Ikuta!
!إيكوتا، أجب عليّ! إيكوتا
Quit playin' around!
!يكفي عبثاً
Ikuta! Ikuta!
...إيكوتا! إيكوتا
He's dead!
!إ-إنّه ميت
What?!
ماذا؟
Ran! Get the police!
!ران! اتّصلي بالشرطة
Right!
!حاضر
A blow to the head with a blunt object...
ضربة للرأس بأداة صُلبة
So many cigarette butts...
الكثير من أعقاب السجائر
The victim is Ikuta Yoshiro-san, 20 years old.
الضحيّة هو إيكوتا يوشيرو-سان، 20 عاماً
A 2nd-year student at Beika University.
طالب في السنة الثانية في جامعة بيكا
And you are?
...وأنت من كان بجانب الضحيّة
Kusaka Masami (20)
(كوساكا ماسامي (20 طالب سنة ثانية، جامعة بيكا
Kusaka. I'm a college friend of Ikuta's.
أُدعى كوساكا، زميل إيكوتا في الجامعة
Could you explain the situation as you found it?
هلّا وضّحت ظروف عثورك عليه؟
Yes.
حاضر
Ikuta and I agreed to meet up here at 10:00 pm.
كان يُفترض أن ألتقي بإيكوتا هنا في تمام العاشرة الليلة
But just as I called out to him, he suddenly collapsed...
...لكن بينما كنتُ أنادي عليه، انهار فجأةً
Did you notice anyone else?
أشاهدت شخصاً آخر وقتها؟
No.
كلا
But it was really too dark to see much...
لكن كان الظلام حالكاً، فلم أستطع الرؤية
With that light broken, I could barely even see Ikuta...
بالكاد استطعتُ رؤية إيكوتا بالأصل مع تحطّم مصباح الشارع
You sure you didn't kill him?
ألم تكن من قتله؟
I didn't do it!
!كـ-كلا
Please let me through!
!د-دعوني أمرّ رجاءً
Hey! Wait!
!أنت! انتظر
Shimizu!
!شيميزو
Kusaka! Why did he die?!
كوساكا! كيف مات إيكوتا؟
Pardon me, but who are you?
المعذرة، من تكون؟
My name's Shimizu.
اسمي شيميزو
Shimizu Yoichi (20)
(20) شيميزو يويتشي طالب سنة ثانية، جامعة بيكا
I was just drinking with Ikuta in our friend's apartment.
كنتُ أشرب مع إيكوتا قبل قليل في شقّة صديقنا
Where would that be?
أين تلك الشقّة؟
There, on the fifth floor.
في الطابق الخامس هناك
Eh?!
ماذا؟
Ikuta was murdered?!
!قُتل إيكوتا؟
Whose apartment is this?
لمن هذه الشقّة؟
lt's mine.
لي أنا
Takeno Koji (20)
(20) تاكينو كوجي طالب سنة ثانية، جامعة بيكا
My name's Takeno. I'm a 2nd-year student along with Ikuta.
أُدعى تاكينو، طالب سنة ثانية في جامعة بيكا مع إيكوتا
And you are?
ومن أنت؟
Nakamura. We're all members of the mountain climbing club.
ناكامورا، كلّنا أعضاء في نادي تسلّق الجبال في جامعة بيكا
Ikuta-san drank with you all here?
كان إيكوتا-سان يشرب معكم هنا؟
Yes, I invited everyone over. We've been here since 7:00...
أجل، دعوتُ الجميع الليلة، وكنّا هنا منذ السابعة
Around what time did Ikuta-san step outside?
متى غادر إيكوتا-سان الغرفة تقريباً؟
A little before 10:00. Kusaka had called at 9:00.
قبل العاشرة بقليل، فكوساكا قد اتّصل عند التاسعة
Hold on! I never called anyone!
!انتظر! لم أتّصل بأحد
That can't be. Right, Takeno?
لا يمكن ذلك، صحيح يا تاكينو؟
Yeah. Ikuta wasn't here, so I answered for him.
أجل، لم يكن إيكوتا موجوداً فأجبتُ مكانه
Where was he?
أين كان وقتها؟
Takeno had asked him to buy snacks at the convenience store.
طلب تاكينو منه الذهاب لشراء أكلات مع الشراب من المتجر
You're certain it was Kusaka-san's voice on the phone?
أأنت متأكد أنّ صوت كوساكا-سان كان على الهاتف؟
Yes. There's no mistake.
أجل، لا شكّ في ذلك
I didn't call!
!لم أتّصل
Then how did you decide where to meet?
كيف رتّبت لمكان لقائكما إذاً؟
Ikuta asked me there. He put a note in my locker.
استدعاني إيكوتا، وضع ملاحظةً في خزانتي في الجامعة
Why did he ask you there?
ولمَ استدعاك؟
Um, well...
...ذ-ذلك
Didn't you say Ikuta took your money?
ألم تقل أنّ إيكوتا أخذ مالك؟
What is he talking about?
ما الموضوع؟
Ikuta took the tuition money I took to school...
أخذ إيكوتا مال رسوم الدراسة ...الذي جلبتُه للجامعة
Do you still have that note of his?
لا تزال ملاحظة الاستدعاء معك؟
No, I threw it out.
كلا، ألقيتُها
Or maybe there never was a note?!
ربما لم تكن موجودةً من البداية
Ikuta-san stole your tuition money and refused to give it back.
سرق إيكوتا-سان مال رسوم دراستك ورفض إعادته مهما ألححت عليه
So you phoned him out of anger and beat him to death!
فاتّصلت به واستدعيته وأنت تستشيط غضباً وضربته حتى الموت
No! Besides, I'm not the only one who hated him!
!كـ-كلا! كما لم أكن الوحيد الذي يمقت إيكوتا
Nakamura and Takeno did too!
!كذلك ناكامورا وتاكينو هناك
Why did I?!
لمَ قد أمقته؟
You owed him lots of money!
!كنتَ تدين له بالكثير من المال وفقما يبدو
I was in here the whole time! Right, Shimizu?
كنتُ هنا طوال الوقت! صحيح يا شيميزو؟
Yeah. But you did step out for some fresh air.
أجل، لكنّك خرجت قليلاً لتستنشق الهواء
Around what time was this?
ومتى كان ذلك؟
Around 10:00, when Ikuta had left.
قُرابة العاشرة، عندما غادر إيكوتا
The same time the incident occurred...
وقت وقوع الجريمة
But it was only for a few minutes!
!لكن كان ذلك لبضعة دقائق فحسب
And why did you have a grudge against Ikuta-san?
ولمَ مقتّ إيكوتا-سان يا تاكينو-سان؟
Ikuta and Togawa Keiko got stranded in the mountains six months ago.
قبل 6 أشهر، تاه إيكوتا وتوغاوا كيكو التي كانت في النادي معنا في الجبال
Ikuta abandoned the injured Keiko and left by himself.
ترك إيكوتا كيكو المصابة ونجا بحياته
She had already frozen to death when we found her.
كانت كيكو مُتجمدةً للموت عندما وجدناها
She and Takeno had been lovers!
كانت على علاقة عاطفية مع تاكينو
Is this true?!
أهذا صحيح؟
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
In mountain accidents, sometimes you have to abandon your friends.
في حوادث الجبال، عليك مسح الدموع وترك أصدقائك للنجاة بنفسك أحياناً
I feel bad about Keiko, but I don't blame Ikuta at all!
أتحسّر على كيكو، لكنّي لا ألوم إيكوتا على ما حصل
Besides, I never took a single step out of this apartment!
كما أنّي لم أخرج من هذه الشقّة البتّة
That's true; he was inside the whole time.
صحيح، كان هنا طوال الوقت
At 10:00, he went to the next room to finish a report for class.
عند العاشرة، ذهب للغرفة المجاورة بمفرده لإنهاء تقرير جامعيّ
How long was he alone?
كم أمضى بمفرده؟
Twenty or thirty minutes...
من عشرين إلى ثلاثين دقيقة
But you can't get outside without going through this room,
لكن لا يمكنك الخروج دون المرور بهذه الغرفة
so I can't see how he could've done it.
فلا أستطيع تخيّل كيف له أن يخرج
But a mountain climber could easily
لكن يمكن لمتسلّق جبال النزول بسهولة
climb down a rope from the window.
عبر حبل من النافذة وما شابه
Not from that window. See for yourself.
ليس من تلك النافذة، تفقّد بنفسك
See?
...رأيت؟ هذه النافذة
That's as far as it goes?
هذا أقصى حد؟
No way anyone could leave through here.
يستحيل أن يخرج أحد من هنا
Say, why did you have the lights off if you were writing a report?
أخبرني، لمَ تركت الأنوار مُطفأة إذا كنت ستكتب تقريراً؟
I saw on the way back from the store.
رأيتُ في طريق عودتي من المتجر
The lights weren't on in this room then.
لم تكن مصابيح هذه الغرفة مضاءة وقتها
Um, well--
...ذ-ذلك
Who cares about that?!
!من يهتمّ؟
As there's no way through that window, Takeno-san is innocent!
،بما أنّ الخروج من هذه النافذة مستحيل تاكينو-سان بريء
A slingshot?
نقَّافة؟
The only phone is in this room?
الهاتف الوحيد في هذه الغرفة؟
A red thread...
...خيط أحمر
Those are the same cigarettes...
هذه نفس السجائر التي كانت في مسرح الجريمة
Ikuta-san must've been a heavy smoker.
أي أنّ إيكوتا-سان كان مدّخناً شرهاً
Alright...
...حسناً
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
Omura-san's apartment is directly below Takeno-san's!
شقّة أومورا-سان أسفل شقّة تاكينو-سان تماماً
Come to think of it, why did the window break then?!
صحيح... لمَ تحطّمت النافذة وقتها؟
Omura's Apartment
شقّة أومورا
Odd. Whatever broke the window isn't in here.
غريب، ما حطّم النافذة ليس موجوداً هنا
Blood!
!دم
Is it the victim's?! But what's it doing here?!
أهو للضحيّة؟ لكن لمَ يوجد على هذه الشظية؟
Isn't this a bloodstain?
أليست هذه بقعة دم؟
What?!
ماذا؟
No question about it!
!لا شكّ في الأمر
Alright! I'll inform Inspector Megure!
!حسناً، سأُعلم المفتّش ميغوري
What's a bloodstain doing here?!
لمَ توجد بقعة دم هنا؟
Ikuta-san was standing here in the dark.
كان إيكوتا-سان يقف هنا في الظلام
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
That bloodstain, the place he was standing,
،بقعة الدم على الحائط، مكان وقوف إيكوتا-سان
and Omura-san's broken window all line up!
!ونافذة أومورا-سان المحطّمة كلّهم بنفس الخطّ
Which means...
...ما يعني
...at the top of this building, there's--
...يوجد على سطح هذا المبنى
A bloodstain!
!ها هي! بقعة دم
And there's Takeno-san's apartment!
وتلك شقّة تاكينو-سان
Now I know who killed him and how!
!عرفتُ هويّة القاتل الآن وكيف ارتكب جريمته
Conan-kun! Where did you go?!
كونان-كن! أين ذهبت؟
Just looking around.
خرجتُ قليلاً فحسب
I'm getting dizzy...
...أشعر بدوار
Could I ask you to come down to the station?
أيمكنكم مرافقتي للمركز حالياً؟
Not so fast, Inspector Megure.
انتظر حضرة المفتّش ميغوري
I will now shed light on the truth of this incident.
سأكشف الآن حقيقة هذه القضيّة
What?!
ماذا؟
The key to this incident is the location of the murder weapon.
مفتاح هذه القضيّة هو مكان سلاح الجريمة
Yes. It was absent from the scene of the crime.
صحيح، لم نجده في مسرح الجريمة
A bloodstain was left behind on the nearby abandoned building,
كانت هناك بقعة دم على المبنى المجاور المهجور
but there's one other place with a bloodstain.
لكن يوجد مكان آخر ببقعة دم
What?! Where?!
ماذا؟! أين؟
I was in Omura's apartment at the time,
كنتُ في شقّة أومورا وقت وقوع الجريمة
but something odd happened.
وحدث أمرٌ غريب
Something odd?
أمر غريب؟
Immediately after the murder, Omura's window shattered.
بعد وقوع الجريمة بلحظات، تحطّمت نافذة أومورا
Does that have to do with this?
ما علاقة ذلك؟
There was blood on the pieces of glass.
كان هناك دم على شظيّة من الزجاج المكسور
What does that entail?
ما معنى ذلك؟
Before I explain, I'd like you to check something.
قبل أن أشرح، أريدكم أن تتفقدوا شيئاً
The roof of the abandoned building.
سطح المبنى المهجور
If I'm correct, there should be blood on the railing
...إن أصبت، ستجدون بقعة دم
directly above the bloodstain on the wall.
على السور فوق بقعة الدم على الحائط مباشرةً
What?!
ماذا؟
Detective Takagi! Go check it out!
محقق تاكاغي، تأكّد فوراً
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Give him a two-way radio.
أعطه جهاز إرسال لاسلكيّ
A radio?
جهاز إرسال لاسلكيّ؟
I'd like him to help with something later on.
أريده أن يساهم بشيء لاحقاً
What the...
...هـ-هذا
Inspector! There's blood on the railing here!
حضرة المفتّش! وجدتها! هناك بقعة دم على السور
What?! Blood on the railing?!
!ماذا؟! دم على السور؟
Just as I suspected.
كما ظننت
What does this mean?
ما معنى هذا؟
The wall, the railing, the glass shards in Omura-san's apartment...
،حائط المبنى المهجور، السور على السطح وشظيّة الزجاج في شقّة أومورا-سان
Why is there blood at these three spots?!
لمَ يوجد دم في هذه المواقع الثلاثة؟
The weapon that killed Ikuta-san passed by those three spots.
مرّ السلاح الذي قتل إيكوتا-سان بهذه المناطق الثلاث
In other words, the killer accomplished his murder from afar.
ما يعني أنّ القاتل ارتكب جريمته دون الاقتراب من مسرحها
Yes. The killer had been in this very room...
...أجل، كان القاتل في هذه الغرفة
It was you, Takeno-san!
!أنت يا تاكينو-سان
What?!
!ماذا؟
No way!
!مستحيل
Are you serious, Mori-san?!
ما الذي تقوله يا موري-سان؟
I couldn't possibly kill him from here!
!يستحيل أن أقتل إيكوتا من هنا
Does anyone have fishing line?
أيحمل أحد خيط صيد؟
Fishing line?
خيط صيد؟
I do.
لديّ واحد
I use it to hang up plastic models.
أستعمله لتعليق نماذجي البلاستيكية
Bring some here.
اجلبه لي
Okay.
حسناً
Ran. Put some rocks in that plastic bag you got earlier.
ران، ضعي صخوراً في الكيس البلاستيكي الذي كانت به الجعّة التي اشتريتِها
Okay.
حاضر
Here you go, Mori.
ها هو يا موري
What're you going to do with this?
ما ستفعل بهذه؟
Now then, Inspector.
إذاً حضرة المفتّش
Tie two strands of fishing line to a rock.
اربط خيطي صيد بصخرة
Alright...
...حسناً
Here, Inspector.
هاك حضرة المفتّش
Once you're done, use Takeno-san's slingshot
بعدما تنتهي، استعمل نقّافة تاكينو-سان
to shoot the rock onto the other building's roof.
في هذه الغرفة لقذف الصخرة نحو سطح المبنى الآخر
It's only a dozen meters away; the length of a few taxicabs.
المسافة عدّة مترات فحسب، بطول سيّارتي أجرة تقريباً
Anyone can shoot it that far.
يمكن لأيّ أحد قذفها
Inspector.
حضرة المفتّش
Have Detective Takagi untie the lines,
اطلب من المحقّق تاكاغي فكّ الخيطين
pass them through the railing, and then tie them together.
وتمريرهما حول السور، ثم ربطهما مُجدداً
Next, the rope on that shelf.
تالياً، الحبل على ذاك الرفّ
Rope? Oh, that?
حبل؟ ذاك؟
Tie one of the lines to one end of it.
اربط خيطاً بطرفه
Like so?
هكذا؟
Now pull the other fishing line in.
اسحب خيط الصيد الآخر الآن
Mori-kun. What do I do with this rope?
موري-كن، ماذا أفعل بهذا الحبل؟
Ran. Tie the bag to the other end of the rope.
ران، اربطي الكيس بطرف الحبل الآخر
Right.
حسناً
Tie it tight so nothing comes out.
اربطيه بشدّة بحيث لا يسقط شيء من المحتوى
All done, Dad!
انتهيت يا أبي
Mori-kun! Don't tell me this is the--
...موري-كن! أيمكن أنّ هذا
Sounds like you've figured it out, too.
...يبدو أنّك عرفت حضرة المفتّش
Inspector! I'm at the spot!
حضرة المفتّش، وصلتُ للمكان
Good! Now we'll start!
!حسناً! سنبدأ
Eh? Start what?
نبدأ ماذا؟
Well, Detective Takagi?!
إذاً يا محقّق تاكاغي؟
The bag passed directly above the chalk lines and hit the wall!
مرّ الكيس فوق مكان وقوع الجثّة !وحدود الطباشير وارتطم بالحائط
It's right next to the bloodstain!
!إنّه بجوار بقعة الدم
Takeno-san murdered Ikuta-san thusly,
هكذا قتل تاكينو-سان إيكوتا-سان
and then pulled the rope in to recover the weapon.
ثمّ سحب الحبل لاسترجاع السلاح فوراً
This would leave no weapon at the murder scene.
هكذا لن يبقى سلاح في مسرح الجريمة
Inspector! The bag just hit below Omura-san's broken window!
حضرة المفتّش! ارتطم الكيس بالحائط !أسفل نافذة أومورا-سان المحطّمة تماماً
Mori! Could that be the thump I heard every night?
موري، أيمكن أنّ صوت الارتطام الذي ...كنتُ أسمعه كلّ ليلة
Yes. Takeno-san had been practicing.
أجل، كان تاكينو-سان يتدرّب
But something unexpected happened tonight:
لكن وقع أمرٌ خارج الحسبان الليلة
the weapon hit the window.
أصاب السلاح النافذة
So that's what broke it...
...ذاك ما حطّمها إذاً
Takeno.
تاكينو
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
Ikuta went down there because Kusaka asked him to on the phone!
ذهب إيكوتا للشارع بذاك المكان !لأنّ كوساكا طلب منه على الهاتف
Had he not called, I couldn't have set that trick up!
!لو لم يتّصل، لما استطعتُ تنفيذ تلك الحيلة
Kusaka-san never called anyone. It was all an act.
لم يتّصل كوساكا-سان بأحد، كانت مسرحيةً أنت بطلها وحدك
But we did hear the phone ring!
!لكننا سمعنا رنين الهاتف
He could make it "ring" at any time
يمكنه جعله يرنّ في أيّ وقت
by recording the sound and setting a timer on it.
عبر تسجيل الصوت وضبط مؤقت ببساطة
All he had left to do was pick up the phone
ما تبقّى هو رفع السمّاعة
and pretend like he was talking to Kusaka-san.
والتظاهر بأنّه يكلّم كوساكا-سان فقط
It was also Takeno-san who put the note in Kusaka-san's locker.
كان تاكينو-سان من وضع الملاحظة في خزانة كوساكا-سان أيضاً بالطبع
All to frame him for Ikuta-san's murder!
!لإلفاق تهمة قتل إيكوتا-سان به
But how did he know where Ikuta-san was standing?
لكن كيف عرف مكان وقوف إيكوتا-سان يا موري-سان؟
It was pitch-black with the streetlight broken...
فالظلام كان حالكاً بسبب تحطّم مصباح الإنارة
Takeno-san broke it in advance to make us think that way.
حطّمه تاكينو-سان مسبقاً لجعلنا نفكّر باستحالة ذلك
Wouldn't that make it harder to know where he'd be?!
ألن يصعب عليه تحديد مكانه هكذا؟
No, he knew where Ikuta-san was, even in the dark.
كلا، كان يعرف أين إيكوتا-سان حتى في الظلام
That's ridiculous. I'm not a bat.
سخافة، لستُ خفّاشاً
Ran.
ران
What was Ikuta-san doing on your way back from the store?
ماذا كان يفعل إيكوتا-سان في طريق عودتك من المتجر؟
Well, he was standing beneath the broken streetlight...
ماذا كان يفعل؟ كان يقف أسفل مصباح الإنارة المحطّم
Oh yeah, and he was smoking!
صحيح... كان يدخّن
As a heavy smoker, Ikuta-san dropped lots of cigarette butts.
أسقط إيكوتا-سان الكثير من أعقاب السجائر لكونه مدّخناً شرهاً
Takeno-san. You aimed at the light from the cigarette
استهدفت نور السيجارة في الظلام يا تاكينو-سان
and dropped the weapon on him.
وأصبته بالسلاح
You had the lights off to prevent anyone from seeing the weapon!
أطفأت أنوار غرفتك كيلا يرى أيّ عابرٍ السلاح
Which means there's a plastic bag full of rocks still in here!
أي أنّ الكيس البلاستيكي المليء بالصخور !الذي سحبته لا يزال في هذه الشقّة
Then check the apartment! I have no plastic bags!
!تفقّدوا الشقّة إذاً! لا كيس بلاستيكي لديّ
Takeno-san.
تاكينو-سان
Those are some thick socks for this time of year.
ترتدي جوارب كثيفة بالنسبة لهذا الوقت من العام
Those are mountain-climbing socks.
هذه جوارب تسلّق جبال
You turned them inside-out and filled them with rocks.
قلبتَها وملأتها بالصخور لتجعلها سلاحاً
Later, you put the rocks in the fish tank and fixed your socks.
بعد الجريمة، ألقيت الصخور في حوض السمك وأعدت جواربك لوضعها
As proof, there's a thread in the water plant!
!والدليل على ذلك هو الخيط العالق بالنبتة المائية
One that's the same color as your socks.
بنفس لون جواربك الحمراء
These are sturdy enough to be used as the weapon and not rip...
هذه متماسكة بما يكفي بحيث تستعملها سلاحاً ولا تتمزق
There should be blood on the inside of those socks.
يُفترض أن يوجد دم داخل هذه الجوارب
Ikuta-san's blood!
!دم إيكوتا-سان
Mind if I have a look, Takeno-san?
هل يمكنني النظر يا تاكينو-سان؟
There's no need.
لا داعي
Takeno!
!تاكينو
Did you do it because of Togawa Keiko-san's death?
أكان دافعك موت توغاوا كيكو-سان؟
Yes.
أجل
As I said, sometimes you have to abandon friends in mountain accidents.
كما قلتُ قبلاً، في حوادث الجبال عليك مسح الدموع وترك أصدقائك للنجاة بنفسك أحياناً
I constantly told myself I couldn't blame Ikuta.
أقنعتُ نفسي باستمرار أنّي لا يجوز أن ألوم إيكوتا
But when I think about never seeing her again,
لكن عندما أفكّر بعدم رؤيتي لها مُجدداً
I feel as if I've been left all alone in this world,
أشعر كما لو أنّي تُركت وحيداً في العالم
I was so lonely that I felt I was going crazy.
غلبتني الوحدة حتّى كدت أفقد صوابي
Then, when I entered a pub one day...
...عندها، عندما دخلت حانةً في أحد الأيام
Yeah, that's right!
نعم، صحيح
Keiko dumped me so I left her to die!
!هجرتني كيكو، لذا تركتها لتلقى حتفها
That's horrible!
!يا لفظاعتك
He had to pay for letting my precious Keiko die for no reason!
لم أستطع مسامحته! ترك عزيزتي كيكو تموت !بسبب سخيف كهذا
And so did Kusaka, who laughed at the story!
!وكذلك كوساكا الذي ضحك على قصّته
Nothing beats beer after solving a crime! It's the greatest!
!ما أروع الجعّة بعد حلّ جريمة
It's getting late; we should call it quits for--
...تأخّر الوقت يا موري، ما رأيك أن نتوقف
Don't say that! Let's get this party goin'!
!لا تقل ذلك! لنحتفل حتّى الصباح
But I'm exhausted...
لكن ألا تشعر بالإرهاق؟
Maybe because you did just have a nap!
بالطبع، ذلك لأنّك غفوت فعلاً
What's the matter, Ran-neechan?
ما الخطب يا ران-نيتشان؟
Tonight was the Tanabata, the one day a year that lovers can meet.
كان اليوم التاناباتا، اليوم الوحيد في العام الذي يلتقي فيه الأحباب
I wonder how Shinichi is doing...
ما الذي يفعله شينتشي يا ترى؟
Ran...
...ران
I'm sure he's looking up at the same starry sky!
!لا بدّ أنّه ينظر لنفس السماء المرصّعة بالنجوم
Yeah...
...أجل
Are you Shiota Heihachiro-san?!
أأنت شيوتا هيهاتشيرو-سان يا جدّ؟
Shiota Heihachiro?!
شيوتا هيهاتشيرو؟
This geezer is that legendary detective?!
!هذا العجوز هو ذاك المتحرّي الأسطوري؟
This was a murder!
!كانت هذه جريمة قتل
Everyone stay where you are!
!ابقوا أماكنكم جميعاً
Darn it! Right before my very eyes!
!تبّاً! أمام ناظريّ
The Stage Actress Murder Case
جريمة قتل ممثلة المسرح
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Vinyl Tape.
شريط فينيل
Next episode features a strange old detective.
يظهر في الحلقة القادمة !متحرّ عجوز غريب الأطوار
Apparently he's Kogoro's master.
!يبدو أنّه معلّم كوغورو